A Finding Aid to the Coulton Waugh and Waugh Family Papers, 1751-1974, bulk 1838-1974, in the Archives of American Art aaa.waugwaug
Archives of American Art
- Assorted Waugh Family papers, 1751-1974; Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet Box 18-19, 30-32, 46, 49
  This series is arranged as 8 subseries.
  4.1: Biographical Materials, circa 1850-1934
  4.2: Correspondence, 1864-1941
  4.3: Writings and Notes, circa 1910-1960s
  4.4: Business and Financial Records, 1921-circa 1960
  4.5: Printed Material, 1751-circa 1970
  4.6: Scrapbooks, circa 1900-circa 1906
  4.7: Photographs, circa 1860-1974
  4.8: Artwork, circa 1840-circa 1960
  Waugh family papers relate to the Waugh Family as a whole as well as specific material from Clara Waugh, Elizabeth Waugh, Gwen Waugh, Ida Waugh, and Odin Waugh.
  - Biographical Materials, circa 1850-1934; 4.1
    Found are biographical sketches and geneaolgical writings for the Waugh family and a prescription for Odin Waugh.
    - Biographical Sketches and Genealogy of Waugh Family, circa 1850-circa 1890 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Prescription, Odin Waugh, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1864-1941; 4.2
    Correspondence is found for Elizabeth, Gwen and Ida Waugh. Letters to Elizabeth Waugh are from book publishers and friends. Gwen Waugh's letters are written to her parents Frederick Judd and Eugenie Waugh. Ida Waugh's letters are written to her husband and from her children.
    - Elizabeth Waugh, 1937-1941 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Gwen Waugh, circa 1910-circa 1913 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Ida Waugh, 1864-1872 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Writings and Notes, circa 1910-1960s; 4.3
    Writings and notes are by Elizabeth Waugh, Clara Waugh, and are on the Waugh family by others.
    - On Hooked Rugs, by Elizabeth Waugh, circa 1930 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Why Artists Die Young," by Elizabeth Waugh, circa 1940 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Poetry, by Clara Waugh, circa 1910 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - On Waugh Family, by Others, circa 1910-1960s (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
  - Business and Financial Records, 1921-circa 1960; 4.4
    Found are documents relating to the works of art owned by the family, and a personal receipt book from Elizabeth Waugh, and a guest book from the Old China Shop, likely owned by Elizabeth Waugh.
    - Works of Art Owned by Waugh Family, circa 1960 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Receipt Book, Elizabeth Waugh, 1921-1922 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Old China Shop Guest Book, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Printed Material, 1751-circa 1970; 4.5
    Found are exibition catalogs, clippings, a collection of historical newspapers, and copies of books written or illustrated by Ida Waugh.
    - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1920-circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1919-1951 (Box 18, Folder 17-20)
    - Historical Newspapers, 1751; 1807-circa 1900 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Holly Berries, by Ida Waugh, 1881 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Belle's Pink Boots, by Joanna H. Mathers, 1881 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      Illustrated by Ida Waugh
  - Scrapbooks, circa 1900-circa 1906; 4.6
    Found are two scrapbooks including a scrapbook complied by Elizabeth Jenkinson and a travel scrapbook. Elizabeth Jenkinson's scrapbook includes works of art and reference material for embroidery projects.
    - Elizabeth Jenkinson Scrapbook, circa 1900 (Box 18, Folder 24)
      Oversized material housed in Box 31, F2
    - Travel Scrapbook, circa 1904 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Oversized Elizabeth Jenkinson Scrapbook, circa 1900 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      From Box 18, F24
  - Photographs, circa 1860-1974; 4.7
    Found are portraits of family members and group photos; snapshots of groups of family members; photos of Waugh family homes; exhibitions; works of art; and a photo album of works of art. Many of the photos are labeled. Within the group photos are many members of the Waugh family including Coulton, Frederick, and Samuel.
    - Portraits and Snapshots of Family and Friends, circa 1860-1945 (Box 18, Folder 26-33)
    - Waugh Family Homes, circa 1890-1930 (Box 18, Folder 34-37)
    - Exhibitions, circa 1940-1974 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Works of Art, circa 1900-1920s (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
    - Negatives, Glass Plates of Works of Art, circa 1900 (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
    - Photo Album, Fragment, circa 1910 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Photo Album of Works of Art, circa 1910 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Oversized Photos of Works of Art, circa 1920 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Artwork and Artifacts, circa 1840-circa 1860; 4.8
    Found are sketches by Elizabeth Waugh, Ida Waugh, Odin Waugh, and unsigned sketches. Also found is a pair of antique spectacles.
    - Elizabeth Waugh Artwork, circa 1913-circa 1940 (Box 19, Folder 7-10)
    - Ida Waugh Artwork, circa 1840-1861 (Box 19, Folder 11-13)
    - Odin Waugh Artwork, circa 1940-circa 1960 (Box 19, Folder 14-16)
    - Unsigned Artwork, circa 1900-circa 1930 (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
    - Antique Spectacles, circa 1830 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Oversized Elizabeth Jenkins Artwork, circa 1900 (Box 47)
    - Oversized Unsigned Art, circa 1850 (Box 50)